A Finding Aid to the Alexander Brook Papers in the Archives of American Art AAA.brooalex
Archives of American Art
Alexander Brook papers
1900-1982
AAA.brooalex
Archives of American Art
4.3 Linear feet
The papers of painter Alexander Brook measure 4.3 linear feet and date from 1900-1982. Found within the papers are biographical material; personal and professional correspondence; writings; personal business records; printed material; scrapbooks; artwork; and photographs of Brook, his family and friends, and his work.
Brook, Alexander, 1898-1980
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The bulk of the papers were donated in several accretions by his Brook's wife, Gina Knee Brook, from 1981 to 1982. In 1982, she loaned a scrapbook for microfilming, which was later donated to the archives by Brook's son, Sandy Brook, in 1994. In 1985 and 1986, the Whitney Museum and Eloise Spaeth each donated a copy of Brook's typescript "Myself and Others."
Related Archival Materials note
The Archives of American Art holds an oral history interview with Alexander Brook conducted by Paul Cummings, July 7-8, 1977. There is also substantial correspondence from Alexander Brook in the Peggy Bacon papers.
Existence and Location of Copies note
The scrapbook that was loaned for microfilming and later donated is also available on microfilm reel 2435.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center. Contact Reference Services for more information.
Separated Materials note
The photocopied typescript, "Myself and Others," was microfilmed upon receipt and is available on reel 3928.
Biographical/Historical note
Alexander Brook (1898-1980) was a painter and art instructor who lived and worked in Woodstock, Sag Harbor, and New York City, New York, and Savannah, Georgia.
Brook was born in Brooklyn, New York to Russian immigrants Eudoxia Gelescu and Onufri Brook. After contracting polio at the age of twelve, he remained bed-ridden for a year and his formal schooling was suspended. At this time, he began to show an interest in art and began receiving his first lessons in painting. In 1914, he enrolled in the Art Students League where he won scholarships and cultivated friendships with other art students, including Louis Bouché, Niles Spencer, and Peggy Bacon, whom he married in 1920.
Brook and Bacon's two children, Belinda and Alexander Bacon Brook, were born in 1920 and 1922, and the couple divided their time between a summer house in Woodstock and a series of apartments in New York City. Their circle of artist friends included the Bouchés, Niles Spencer, Yasuo Kuniyoshi, Andrew Dasburg, and many of the other artists who lived and worked in Woodstock. Brook and Bacon continued to produce art, with Brook focusing on his painting, and Bacon publishing her illustrations and prints in nationally syndicated magazines.
In the 1920s, Brook also wrote articles for The Arts and caught the attention of Gertrude Vanderbilt Whitney. She invited him to promote and organize exhibits for her Whitney Studio Club, and from 1923 to 1927, he worked as assistant director of the Club, which was later to become the Whitney Museum of Art. By the late 1920s, Brook's realist paintings of landscapes, still lifes, and posed figures of women were gaining wide recognition and he was given his first retrospective at the Art Institute of Chicago in 1929, at the age of thirty-one. In the early 1930s, within the span of three years, Brook exhibited one man shows at the ACA, Valentine, Charles Daniel, and Downtown Galleries in New York City, and received a Guggenheim Fellowship in 1931.
In 1938, Brook moved to Savannah, Georgia and began visiting and painting realist scenes based on visits to the city's oldest black neighborhoods. When Brook's marriage with Bacon ended in 1940, he continued to live in Savannah with his second wife, Libby Berger. After his second marriage ended, he returned to New York in 1942 to teach at the Art Students League and, during World War II, served as a correspondent and artist for the Army based out of Panama.
In 1944, Brook returned to Savannah with his third wife, the artist Gina Knee Brook. Through the mid-1940s, Brook continued to exhibit his works, primarily through the Rehn Gallery, contributed articles and essays to art journals, and was commissioned to paint two covers for the Saturday Evening Post. In 1948, the Brooks purchased and moved to their last home in Sag Harbor, Long Island. Believing realist work was no longer well received in critical and contemporary art circles, Brook slowly retreated from the art world, exhibiting his last solo show at Knoedler Galleries in 1952, and retiring from painting in 1966. Brook died on February 26, 1980.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of painter Alexander Brook measure 4.3 linear feet and date from 1900-1982. Found within the papers are biographical material; personal and professional correspondence; writings; personal business records; printed material; scrapbooks; artwork; and photographs of Brook, his family and friends, and his work.
Biographical materials include an address book, award certificates, curriculum vitae, marriage and divorce documents, passports, biographical information on Brook's wife, Gina Knee Brook, and 4 interview transcripts.
Correspondence is primarily with Brook's family, friends, fellow artists, and business associates discussing personal relationships, teaching opportunities, art sales, and exhibitions. Included in this series are letters to Brook's second wife, Gina Knee Brook. Additional correspondents include Brook's children, Belinda and Sandy (Alexander) Brook, Peggy Bacon, artists Niles Spencer and George Biddle, and writer Haniel Long.
Writings by Brook consist of reminiscences, 6 essays, a lecture, a memorium to Catherine Brett, 6 short stories, 2 notebooks, and miscellaneous notes. Writings by others consist of a notebook by Mrs. Beeton containing humorous recipes, an essay, 2 memoirs, poetry, and a short story from unknown authors.
Personal business records include sales invoices, tax returns noting income from sales of artwork, and receipts for various art supplies.
Printed material includes brochures, chapbooks, clippings, city guides, exhibition announcements and catalogs, periodicals, and miscellaneous printed material.
There are two scrapbooks, a clippings scrapbook titled Unstruggling Artist, and an untitled scrapbook containing clippings and interspersed with correspondence, catalogs, and photographs.
Artwork consists of ink, pencil, and pen sketches; etchings and 2 etching plates; mixed media illustrations; and watercolors by unknown artists. There are also 9 sketchbooks, most likely by Alexander Brook, and a drawing by Miguel Covarrubius.
Photographs are of people, exhibition installations, and works of art. These include childhood photos of Alexander Brook and Gina Knee Brook, photos of the Brooks together in Savannah, Georgia and Sag Harbor, Long Island, as well as photos of Alexander Brook with friends, an artist model, at home, and in various studios. There are also photos of Peggy Bacon, Louis Bouché, Niles Spencer, and Jackson Pollock. Exhibition installations include a show at the Carnegie Institution and unidentified one man shows.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 8 series.
Series 1: Biographical Materials, 1907-1979 (14 folders; Box 1)
Series 2: Correspondence, circa 1930-1975 (0.6 linear feet; Box 1)
Series 3: Writings, circa 1921-1975 (0.5 linear feet; Box 1-2)
Series 4: Personal Business Records, circa 1931-1982 (0.3 linear feet; Box 2)
Series 5: Printed Material, 1918-1982 (1.4 linear feet; Box 2-3)
Series 6: Scrapbooks, circa 1935-1975 (0.4 linear feet; Box 3, 5)
Series 7: Artwork, circa 1935-1975 (0.4 linear feet; Box 4)
Series 8: Photographs, circa 1900-1980 (0.6 linear feet; Box 4)
Bacon, Peggy, 1895-1987; Biddle, George, 1885-1973; Bouché, Louis, 1896-1969; Brett, Catherine; Covarrubias, Miguel, 1904-1957; Knee, Gina, 1898-1982; Pollock, Jackson, 1912-1956; Spencer, Niles, 1893-1952; Etchings; Illustrations; Interviews; Painters--New York (State)--New York; Painting, Modern--20th century--New York (State)--New York; Photographs; Post-impressionism (Art)--United States--New York (State)--New York; Scrapbooks; Sketchbooks; Sketches; Transcriptions; Watercolors
- Biographical Materials, 1907-1979; Series 1; 14 Folders Box 1
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical materials include an address book, award certificates, curriculum vitae, marriage and divorce documents, passports, biographical information on Brook's wife, Gina Knee Brook, and 4 interview transcripts. There are also a handful of documents from other Brook family members, Alexander Brook's fingerprints and driver's license, a kidney stone, and a war ration book dating from World War II.
  Arrangement note
  Materials are arranged by document type. Interviews are filed in chronological order.
  - Address Book, circa 1940-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Awards, 1949-1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Curriculum Vitae, 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Family Certificates and Letter, circa 1935-1975 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Fingerprints and Registration, 1943-1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Kidney Stone, circa 1950-1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Legal Contracts, 1922-1949 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Passports, 1931-1952 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - War Ration Book, circa 1943 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Gina Knee Brook, Certificate and Reports, 1907; 1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Interview with Radio Show, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Interview with Unidentified Interviewer, circa 1938 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Interview with Del Hester and Ethel Grey, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Interview with Unidentified Interviewer, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Correspondence, circa 1930-1975; Series 2; 0.6 Linear feet Box 1
  Correspondence is primarily with Brook's family, friends, fellow artists, and business associates discussing personal relationships, teaching opportunities, art sales, and exhibitions. Included in this series are letters addressed directly to Brook's second wife, Gina Knee Brook. Correspondents of note include Brook's children, Belinda and Sandy (Alexander) Brook, his wife from his first marriage, Peggy Bacon, the artists Niles Spencer, and George Biddle, and the writer Haniel Long.
  This series also includes letters from Theodore Roosevelt, Katharine Hepburn, Abraham Walkowitz, and Eloise Spaeth; letters forwarded by the Saturday Evening Post from readers responding to Brook's cover artwork for the magazine in 1945 and 1946; correspondence from students at the Brett School, which was founded by Brook's friend Catherine Brett; and letters in Spanish from friends in Spain.
  All correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent, followed by letters from Spain, and unidentified, illegible, and unsigned letters.
  - A Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1968-1978 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Archives of American Art, 1967-1976 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - B Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bacon, Peggy Brook, 1937-1976 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Brett School, 1950-1964 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Brook, Alexander, circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Brook, Belinda, 1947-1968 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Brook, Gina Knee, 1944-1968 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Brook, Sandy, 1941-1978 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Butler Institute of American Art, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - C Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Choate School, 1936-1937 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - D Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Dayton Art Institute, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - E-F Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Ford Foundation, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - G Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Gale, Bernays, Falk, and Eisner, 1945-1947 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - H Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Houston, Katharine Baker, 1934-1939 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - I-L Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Lamb, Walter, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Long, Haniel, 1937-1956 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - M Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Marter, Joan M., 1976 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - N-P Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Q-R Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Rumania Institut for Cultural Relations, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - S Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Saturday Evening Post, 1945-1946, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 45-46)
  - T Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Telfair Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1948-1972 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - U-W Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Whitney Museum, 1953-1975 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Y-Z Miscellaneous, circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Letters from Spain, 1955-1968 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Unknown and Illegible, circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 53)
- Writings, circa 1921-1975; Series 3; 0.5 Linear feet Box 1-2
  Writings by Brook consist of reminiscence vignettes,, portions of which comprise chapters in his memoir, "Myself and Others." There are also 6 essays on art criticism, Alexander Calder, and personal philosophies on art; a lecture; a memorium to Catherine Brett, the founder of the Brett School; 6 short stories; 2 notebooks of writing fragments; and miscellaneous notes.
  Writings by others consist of a notebook by Mrs. Beeton containing humorous recipes, an essay, 2 memoirs, poetry, and a short story from unknown authors.
  Materials are arranged by document type.
  - By Alexander Brook (Box 1)
    - Drafts, Reminiscences, circa 1960-1975 (Box 1, Folder 54-58)
    - Drafts, Reminiscences, Edits, circa 1960-1975 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Essay, "Art, Where Are Thou?", 1963 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    - Essay, On Alexander Calder, circa 1950-1975 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    - Essay, On Altamira and Lascaux Caves, circa 1953 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Essay, On Art Critics, circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Essay, On Lyme Art Colony, circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - Essay, "Unabashed Ravings of a Sane and Logical Man", 1976 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Lecture, "Artist's Viewpoint", circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - Memorium, For Catherine Brett, circa 1960-1975 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    - Short Story, Brooklyn Vignette, circa 1921 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    - Short Story, Car Purchase, circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    - Short Story, "Jensen's Misadventure", circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 70-71)
    - Short Story, Jonathan Thomas, circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Short Story, Revolver, circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Short Story, "Triumph", circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Notebooks, circa 1930-1975 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Notes, circa 1935-1975 (Box 2, Folder 1-3)
  - By Others (Box 2)
    - Beeton, Notebook, Recipes, circa 1935-1960 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Unknown, Essay, On Public Art, circa 1935-1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Unknown, Memoir, "Journey's Journal", circa 1935-1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Unknown, Memoir, "Zombis", circa 1935-1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Unknown, Poetry, circa 1935-1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Unknown, Short Story, "Fish Bowl Mystery", circa 1935-1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Personal Business Records, circa 1931-1982; Series 4; 0.3 Linear feet Box 2
  Personal business records include sales invoices, tax returns noting income from sales of artwork, and receipts for various art supplies. Notes on sales purchasers and prices; 2 checkbook registers of outgoing expenses; and correspondence consisting of price lists and sales invoices from art galleries, including the Downtown and Rehn Galleries are included in this series.
  Items are arranged chronologically by document type.
  - Invoices, Tax Returns, and Receipts, circa 1930-1975 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Invoices, Tax Returns, and Receipts, 1931-1952 (Box 2, Folder 11-15)
  - Invoices, Tax Returns, and Receipts, 1953-1974 (Box 2, Folder 16-20)
  - Price Lists, 1949-1982 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Printed Material, 1918-1982; Series 5; 1.4 Linear feet Box 2-3
  Printed material includes brochures, chapbooks, clippings, city guides for the cities of Charleston and Savannah, exhibition announcements and catalogs, art related periodicals, and miscellaneous printed material.
  The cover design of the book Toward the Western Sky is by Gina Knee Brook.
  - Book, Gallery of Living Art, 1933 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Book, Holter, Sage, This, My Earth, 1942 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Book, Houvet, Etienne, Illustrated Monograph of Chartres Cathedral, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Book, Riggs, Lynn, Toward the Western Sky (play), 1951 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Brochures, 1930-1953 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Bulletins, 1939-1956 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Chapbooks, 1940, 1944 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Clippings, circa 1927-1975 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Clippings, 1922-1935 (Box 2, Folder 30-34)
  - Clippings, 1936-1946 (Box 2, Folder 35-39)
  - Clippings, 1947-1982 (Box 2, Folder 40-45)
  - City Guides, Charleston and Savannah, circa 1940s (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1922-1931 (Box 2, Folder 47-48)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1932-1943 (Box 3, Folder 1-5)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1944-1982 (Box 3, Folder 6-10)
  - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, Gina Knee Brook, 1931-1964 (Box 3, Folder 11-12)
  - Exhibition Announcements, Other Artists, 1943-1982 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Other Artists, 1935-1944; 1918 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, Other Artists, 1945-1979 (Box 3, Folder 15-17)
  - Greeting Cards and Postcards, circa 1940-1975 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Periodical, '47 The Magazine of the Year, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Periodical, Art News, 1930-1935 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Periodical, Art Review, 1922 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Periodical, Arts, 1924, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Periodical, Carnegie Magazine, 1933-1948 (Box 3, Folder 23-25)
  - Periodical, Horse Fly, 1938-1941 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Periodical, Hue and Cry, 1925 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Periodical, Little Review, 1923-1924 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Periodical, News from the Art World, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Periodical, Survey Graphic, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, circa 1930-1975 (Box 3, Folder 31)
- Scrapbooks, circa 1935-1975; Series 6; 0.4 Linear feet Box 3, 5
  There are two scrapbooks, a clippings scrapbook titled Unstruggling Artist, and an untitled scrapbook containing clippings and interspersed with correspondence, catalogs, and photographs.
  Both scrapbooks were gifted to Alexander Brook. Unstruggling Artist was designed by G. Alan Chidsey and is comprised of a 1936 article appearing in Esquire magazine. The untitled scrapbook documents Brook's midcareer up to 1946 and includes additional loose material dating from circa 1946-1976. These materials include professional certificates, cards, correspondence, lists, notes, clippings, and 14 oversize photographs of Alexander Brook, Gina Knee Brook, and a work of art.
  Materials are arranged by item title.
  - Unstruggling Artist, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Untitled Scrapbook, circa 1930-1976 (Box 5)
- Artwork, circa 1935-1975; Series 7; 0.4 Linear feet Box 4
  Artwork consists of ink, pencil, and pen sketches; etchings and 2 etching plates; mixed media illustrations; and watercolors by unknown artists. The sketches include children's illustration, jewelry designs, southwestern landscapes, and portraits and characters. The etching plates are figures of women, and the etchings are of groups of figures. The mixed media children's illustrations likely go with the manuscript "Fish Bowl Mystery." There are also 9 sketchbooks that include figures, portraits, landscapes, and animals, most likely by Alexander Brook, and a drawing by Miguel Covarrubius.
  Artwork is arranged by artist and media type.
  - Covarrubius, Miguel, Caricature of Alexander Brook, circa 1935-1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Unknown Artist (Box 4)
    - Drawings, Children's Illustration, circa 1935-1975 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Drawings, Jewelry Design, circa 1935-1975 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Drawings, Landscapes, circa 1935-1975 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Drawings, Portraits and Caricatures, circa 1935-1975 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Etching Plates, circa 1935-1975 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Etchings, circa 1935-1975 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Mixed Media, Children's Illustration, circa 1935-1975 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Watercolors, New Mexico, circa 1935-1975 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Likely by Alexander Brook (Box 4)
    - Sketchbooks, circa 1935-1975 (Box 4, Folder 10-14)
    - Sketchbooks, circa 1935-1975 (Box 4, Folder 15-16)
- Photographs, circa 1900-1980; Series 8; 0.6 Linear feet Box 4
  Photographs are of people, exhibition installations, and works of art. These include childhood photos of Alexander Brook and Gina Knee Brook, photos of the Brooks together in Savannah, Georgia and Sag Harbor, Long Island, as well as photos of Alexander Brook with friends, an artist model, at home, and in various studios. Within the photos of Alexander Brook are two series of the artist in his studio, one shot by Peter Stackpole in 1943, and one shot by Gabriel Benzur in 1946. The photographs of Alexander Brook posing with an artist model were taken by Hans Namuth in 1980.
  There are also photos of the Brook's extended family, his car, travel to the southwest, and the artists Peggy Bacon, Louis Bouché, Niles Spencer, and Jackson Pollock. Exhibition installations include a show at the Carnegie Institution and unidentified one man shows. There are additional oversize photos found in the untitled scrapbook in the Scrapbook series.
  Items are arranged by subject and material type.
  - Photographs of Alexander Brook, 1910-1980 (Box 4, Folder 17-19)
  - Contact Sheets of Alexander Brook, circa 1940-1975 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Photographs of Alexander Brook and Gina Knee Brook, circa 1945-1980 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Photographs of Alexander Brook with Jackson Pollock, 1934 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Photographs of Alexander Brook, Louis Bouché, and Niles Spencer, circa 1940s (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Photographs of Alexander Brook with Model, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Photographs of Gina Knee Brook, circa 1910-1975 (Box 4, Folder 25-26)
  - Photograph of Peggy Bacon, circa 1920 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Photographs of Brook Family, circa 1900-1960 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Photographs of Friends, circa 1910-1976 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Photographs of Brook, Knee, and Spencer Houses, circa 1920-1975 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Photographs of Car, circa 1958-1965 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Photographs of Travel, circa 1930-1970 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Photographs of Works of Art, On Display, circa 1940-1975 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Photographs of Works of Art, Sketches, circa 1920-1975 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Photographs of Works of Art, Abstracts, circa 1920-1975 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Photographs of Works of Art, Houses, circa 1920-1975 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Photographs of Works of Art, Landscapes, circa 1920-1975 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Photographs of Works of Art, New Mexico, circa 1920-1975 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Photographs of Works of Art, Still Lifes, circa 1920-1975 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Photographs of Works of Art, Children, circa 1920-1975 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Photographs of Works of Art, Men, circa 1920-1975 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Photographs of Works of Art, Women, circa 1920-1975 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Photographs of Works of Art, Women, Half Dressed, circa 1920-1975 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Photographs of Works of Art, Women, Nudes, circa 1920-1975 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Photographs of Works of Art, Women, Portraits, circa 1920-1975 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Photographs of Works of Art, By Others, circa 1920-1975 (Box 4, Folder 46)